

in /leo-ribas ☑ Iribas.uxr@pm.me (+33 7 68 55 43 60

SIGNIFICANT PROJECTS

PlunetBoard - A New Dashboard For The Service

Plunet GmbH

I contributed to the creation of a modern dashboard for the software service. My input helped to streamline the prioritization of widget development, guided data filtering decisions, and resolved critical usability issues.

My contributions included:

- Analyzing focus groups discussions
- Leading design workshops
- Addressing key questions with surveys
- Moderating usability tests

Plunet BusinessManager - Improving Usability

■ Plunet GmbH

I established a long-term research project to evaluate the usability of Plunet BusinessManager and monitor its development. This initiative has fostered collective awareness of the software's usability and accessibility, guiding key decisions on front-end technology.

My contributions included:

- Conducting internal workshops to identify the Product Team needs
- Managing research using standardized usability questionnaires (CSUQ)
- Investigating the accessibility needs of users

User Insights - Driving Collaborative Decision-Making

Plunet GmbH

I played an integral role in multiple projects within Plunet's Product Team, where I streamlined decisionmaking by delivering actionable insights to stakeholders.

Specifically:

- I designed and tested wireframes and interface prototypes
- I established a comprehensive contact base to support the team's research initiatives
- I conducted interviews and surveys, generating valuable insights
- I facilitated interface design by organizing workshops and collaborating closely with designers

WORK EXPERIENCES

UX Researcher

March 2022 - Now

UX researcher responsible for all user research within the Plunet Product Team.

Plunet GmbH

🗣 Berlin

Online

Part-time University Lecturer

III January 2024 - Now

Teaching the "Introduction to UX and usability" module for a Master's degree in Multilingual Web Communication (Master CAWEB).

University of Strasbourg

Customer Care Agent

.... March 2019 - January 2021

Customer support for transportation tickets dealer, transport companies and roadside assistance.

Majorel GmbH - Omio GmbH

Research assistant

February 2018 - July 2018

For my Master's thesis, I worked at the Institut de Neurosciences Cognitives et Intégratives d'Aquitaine. My project focused on the relationship between associative memory and emotion. **INCIA** Neurocampus

October - December 2021

Bordeaux

II Ironhack

Berlin

SKILLS

UX Strategy

Area of expertise

Research & Analysis

Qualitative & Quantitative Methodology

Wireframing & Protoyping | Usability Testing

Psychology & Cognitive Science

Tools

Collaborative Design (Figma)

Quantitative Analysis (Excel, SPSS)

Qualitative Analysis (Condens)

Language

French (native)

German (intermediate)

English (fluent)

& Ecology

Technology, Ergonomics and

EDUCATION

UX/UI Design Program

Master's degree in

Cognitive Science

Handicap Program

Ironhack Bootcamp

September 2015 - July 2018

University of Bordeaux

University of Perpignan

Perpignan

Bordeaux